# **Bhavya Arora**

- B-164/Mohan Gaden/New Delhi 59, New Delhi, Delhi 110059
- gobhavyaarora15@gmail.com
- (870) 035-9115



## **Professional Summary**

Software Engineer with Experience in many languages, tools and Platforms. Has a Good Problem Solving skills and has Experience in many Projects. Proficient in Android Development, Project Management. Worked on some Big Level Projects, Scaled those projects even bigger with Creative Skills



## **Employment history**

#### Android Developer, Appssage. Noida, Uttar Pradesh

Mar. 2019 - Present

Working as Android and Node.JS Developer.

## Internshala Student Partner, Internshala. New Delhi, Delhi Jun. 2018 – Aug. 2018

- Role is to Promote Internshala trainings and tell fellow mates that they
  can find Internships at Internshala through my Programming Skills.
- · Host Seminars and Workshops in College.

# Android and Python Developer(Intern), AllFriendStudio. New, Delhi

Jun. 2018 - Jul. 2018

- Worked on Firebase in Android to make 100 calls per second to check what's the firebase capabilities.
- Write a Python Socket Program which can listen to Node.js Server. So that we can Control Raspberry Pi LED with Android App.

## Android Developer(Intern), PG Infotech. New Delhi, Delhi Jun. 2018 – Jul. 2018

Develop Application for Doctors to Store their data in mobile locally. So no more need of Registers( Using SQlite).



## Education

### World College of Technology and Management., New Delhi, Delhi

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science, Present

## kamal model sr sec school, New, Delhi

12th - CBSE, Science( with 80% ), Apr. 2014

## kamal model sr sec school, New Delhi, Delhi

10th - CBSE, (with 69%), Apr. 2012



## Skills

SQL

Html | Css | Css3 | Javascript

Git | Github

Python

Node.js | Express.js

Firebase

Android Development



- GOOGLE INDIA CHALLENGE SCHOLARSHIP 2018
- INTRODUCTION TO MODERN APPLICATION AND DEVELOPMENT ( NPTEL - Associated with IIT MADRAS) - 2017



# **Personal Projects**

#### DOCTORAVE:

Google Play Link: https://play.google.com/store

/apps/details?id=com.id.drapp

Description: This is a Open Source app which I developed for

**Doctors and Patients** 

#### · Math Enough:

Google play link: https://play.google.com/store /apps/details?id=games.googoo.mathenough

Description: Mathematical Game which uses BODMAS and randomly Generating everything.

### . CHAT APP:

Description: This the Chat App in which anyone can join the Room and can chat with others. I integrated Typing Indicator, Message will show if any person will join/leave the room.

Tools/Languages used: I used SocketIO as Medium of transfer of messages. Node.js for Server which is Deployed on Heroku and Android App( Client ) can talk to Node.js Socket Server.

#### REALTIME MAPS TRACKING APP:

Description: This is Realtime Tracking app. Basically this project consist of two apps. One is use see another moving app realtime location.

Tools/Languages used: Google Maps API for using Google Maps Fragment in Android App and SocketIO for transferring realtime Latitude and Longitude in another App.

#### WEB PROJECT:

Description: This is the college project in which I made a Full Website Frontend and Backend as well.

Tools/Languages used: #Frontend( Html, Css, Css3, Javascript )

#Backend( Node.js, PostgreSQL )

#Deployed on Heroku



# Portfolio or Links

- GITHUB: https://github.com/bhavya-arora
- LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bhavyaarora28/
- . WEBSITE: https://bhavya-arora.github.io